Henry DeWolf Smyth Papers 1885-1987 Mss.Ms.Coll.15
American Philosophical Society
- Series III. Atomic Energy Commission Subject Files, 1949-75
  - AEC Views on IAEA Nuclear Data Activities, 1966
    INDSWG (Int'l Nuclear Data Sci. Working Group)
  - Barter Arrangements, 1965; n.d.
  - Chairmanship, 1971
    Schlesinger
  - Citation, 1967
    Abelson, Philip H.
    Dulles, Allen W.
    Eklund, Sigvard
    Gevantman, Lewis H.
    Johnston, L. E.
    Kratzer, Myron B.
    McCormack, James
    McKnight, A. D.
    Morehouse, E. W.
    Rusk, Dean
    Wigner, Eugene P.
    press releases, photos
  - Civilian Atomic Industry Regulations
    - Folder #1, 1955-56
    - Folder #2, 1956
  - Commissioners' terms, n.d.
  - England, Brussels & Paris, Smyth trip to, Jul. 1952
    Cherwell, [?] (Lord)
    Cockcroft, John (Sir)
    France, Arthur Robert E.
    Makins, Roger (Sir)
    Morgan, Frederick (Sir)
    Rowlands, Archibald (Sir)
    Sandys, Duncan
    itinerary, diary, re: cooperation
  - Fellowship Program, 1950-51
    Higinbotham, W. A.
    Klopsteg, Paul E.
    Mitchell, Allen C. G.
    Pitzer, Kenneth S.
    re: security clearance, loyalty and non-communist oaths
  - [Fermi Award to Oppenheimer], 1963
    Leake, Chauncey D.
    McCool, Woodford B.
    Oppenheimer, J. Robert
    Smyth, Mary [deC.]
    clippings, press releases
  - Foreign Visitors, 1952-54
    security forms
  - General Advisory Committee. Candidates, 1952
    Arneson, Gordon
    Dawson, Donald
    Fisk, James Brown
    Glennan, T. Keith
  - General Manager. Candidates, 1953-54
    Snapp, Roy B.
    Strauss, Lewis L.
    Waters, J. A.
    biographical sketches
  - Idaho SL-1 Reactor Accident
    Axtmann, R. C.
    Brown, G. Edwin, Jr.
    Weaver, Charles H.
    Wiggin, Edwin A.
    - Folder #1-2, 1961
  - Joint Committee on Atomic Energy. U.S. - Israeli Agreement, 1964-65
    Conway, John T.
    Hollingsworth, R. E.
    Johnson, Lyndon B.
    Palfrey, John G.
  - Memoranda, 1949-58; n.d.
    JRO case, AEC business
  - Munich and Salzburg Conferences, Key Facts About, 1961
  - Operation Castle, 1954 (Box Series III-2)
    bomb tests, Joint Task Force Seven
  - Operation Greenhouse, Apr. 1951
    bomb tests, Joint Task Force Three
  - Oppenheimer, J. Robert
    -See Ser. VIII, Dissenting opinion of HDS in the matter of J. Robert Oppenheimer, 1954 [in U.S. AEC "Statement by the AEC"]
  - President's Proposal, 1952; 1975
    -See also Ser. I, Strauss, Lewis L., memos dated 10 & 15 Feb. 1954
    re: Eisenhower's 8 Dec. 1953 speech
  - [Press conference at the International Conference for the Peaceful Uses of Atomic Energy], 1955
    Libby, [Willard F.]
    McKnight, John P.
    Weil, George
    transcript
  - Press Digest, 1949
    clippings service
  - Press Releases, 1949; 1954-67
    -See also Ser. VIII, Dissenting opinion of HDS in the matter of J. Robert Oppenheimer, 1954 [in U.S. AEC "Statement by the AEC"]
  - Reactor Policies and Programs, Ad Hoc Advisory Committee on
    Anderson, Clinton P.
    Black, James
    Boyer, Marion
    Brooks, Harvey
    Fine, Paul C.
    Floberg, John F.
    Foster, Paul F.
    Grahl, James L.
    Hammond, R. Philip
    Hilberry, Norman
    Kauffman, J [ack]
    Landis, J. W.
    Lane, James A.
    Lindseth, Elmer L.
    McCone, John A.
    McCune, Francis K.
    Miles, F. T.
    Radin, Alex
    Ramey, James T.
    Staebler, U. M.
    Tammaro, A [1]
    Weinberg, Alvin M.
    Wilson, Robert E.
    Zinn, W. H.
    -See also Ser. IX, Weinberg, Alvin M., Some Thoughts on Reactors
    minutes, corresp., press releases, drafts, reports civilian power reactor devel.
    - Folder #1, 1956-58
      uranium, thorium
    - Folders #2-3, 1958
    - Folder #4, 1959
  - Reactor Policies and Programs, Ad Hoc Advisory Committee on (Box Series III-3)
    - Folder #5, 1959
    - Folder #6, 1959-60
  - Reactor Policies and Programs, Ad Hoc Advisory Committee on. Proceedings
    meeting transcripts
    - Folder #1, 28 Oct. 1958
    - Folder #2, 29 Nov. 1958
    - Folder #3, 10 Dec. 1958
    - Folder #4, 11 Dec. 1958
    - Folder #5, 22 Dec. 1958
    - Folder #6, 23 Dec. 1958
  - Reactor Policies and Programs, Ad Hoc Advisory Committee on. Statistical charts & data, Oct.-Nov. 1958
  - Research policy, n.d. (Box Series III-4)
    notes
  - Russian atomic explosions, 1951; 1953
    Cole, Sterling
    English, [S. G.]
    Lakin, Frank C.
    Lay, James
    Salisbury, [Morse]
    re: A- and H bomb explosions
  - Safeguarding Special Nuclear Material, Ad Hoc Advisory Panel on. Report, 1966-67
    Hall, John A.
    Lumb, R. F.
    McKnight, Allan D.
    Nakicenovic, S.
    Taylor, Theodore B.
  - Savannah River Project, 1952
    Cook, R. W.
    Dunbar, Leslie W.
    Fogarty, James W.
    Silvey, Ted F.
    Towne, Carroll A.
    re: problems of reactors sited in small rural towns
  - Scientific manpower, 1950-51
    Bacher, Robert F.
    Boskey, Bennett
    Clark, Robert L.
    Compton, Karl T.
    Hafstad, L. R.
    Hershey, Lewis B.
    Johnson, Ellis A.
    Trytten, M. H.
  - Security clearance, n.d.
    AEC "Q" clearance
  - Shippingport Project, Ad Hoc Committee to Evaluate the, 1960
    minutes, report
  - Shippingport Project. Review of the Pressurized Water Reactor (PWR) Program, 14 Jan. 1960
  - Strauss, Lewis L. - Confirmation, 1959; n.d.
    American Physical Society
    Condon, E. U.
    re: hearing, MdeCS diary extracts
  - Thermonuclear weapons program, 1949-54
    DuBridge, Lee A.
    Lilienthal, David E.
    Pike, Sumner T.
    Shugg, Carleton
    Washington Post, The
    Weil, George L.
    Wilson, Charles E.
    opinions
  - Thermonuclear weapons program chronology, 1974
  - U.S. Participation in the IAEA. Report to the General Manager by the Director, Division of International Affairs, 1961
- Series IV. International Atomic Energy Agency Subject Files, 1953-1986
  contains correspondence, reports, calendars, invitations, press releases, photographs, information circulars, and other miscellaneous documents acquired by Smyth during and after his work for the IAEA as U.S. Ambassador. The bulk of the IAEA related material dates from the 1960s, during Smyth's most active years in association with this organization. The IAEA subject files are arranged alphabetically within the series and then chronologically within each folder.
  Correspondence is generally found within subject files containing a variety of items, such as reports, meeting agendas, and miscellaneous committee business. All correspondents throughout the IAEA subject files are listed on the outside of folders (folder #1 in cases of multiple folders per subject) and are cross referenced to Series I, Professional Correspondence.
  Most of the larger subject files, consisting of multiple folders, pertain to the IAEA annual General Conference and the Board of Governors. These files contain reports which follow a chronological arrangement; each type of report has been assigned a detailed numbering system which has been reproduced as folder titles (i.e., Board of Governors/COM.8/OR.29-COM.18/OR.5). Short descriptions of each type of report are available in the "Notes" column of the container list. While the folders containing these documents are extensive, researchers should note that they are not always complete; in some cases, a gap in the chronological arrangement exists, with reports missing from the consecutive numbering system.
  Other subject files document a variety of IAEA concerns and projects. Material dealing with nuclear safeguards, the Nonproliferation Treaty (1970), the Tarapur Project (1962-63), the Atoms for Peace Conferences (1958; 1964), and the International Centre for Theoretical Physics in Trieste (1963-68) is located throughout Series IV. These files often contain meeting agendas and minutes, reports, and correspondence.
  - Advancement in the technology of atomic energy. Australia, n.d. (Box Series IV-1)
  - Advancement in the technology of atomic energy. Argentina, n.d.
  - Advancement in the technology of atomic energy. Brazil, n.d.
  - Advancement in the technology of atomic energy. Germany, n.d.
  - Advancement in the technology of atomic energy. India
  - Advancement in the technology of atomic energy. Italy, n.d.
  - Advancement in the technology of atomic energy. Japan, n.d.
  - Advancement in the technology of atomic energy. South Africa, n.d.
  - Advancement in the technology of atomic energy. Spain, n.d.
  - Advancement in the technology of atomic energy. Sweden, n.d.
  - [Agency safeguards], n.d.
  - Agreed communique, 25 Jul. 1963
  - Appointment to the IAEA, 1961
  - Apollo 12, 1970
    Jacques, Philippe G.
    Lewis, Verne B.
    includes photos
  - Atoms for peace program. Chronology of important events in the, Dec. 1953-Jun. 1965
  - Biographical information, n.d.
    IAEA members
  - Board of Governors, n.d.
  - Board of Governors, 1958-63
  - Board of Governors luncheon, 28 Jul. 1970
  - Board of Governors. Meeting 391, 15 Jun. 1967
    partial transcript
  - Board of Governors. Officers since 1957, 1970
  - Board of Governors/
    provisional agenda items
    - Folder #1 1228-1373, 1967-69
    - Folder #2 1374-1391, 1969-70
    - Folder #3 1392-1432, 1970
    - Folder #4 1444-1560, 1971-72
  - Board of Governors/
    committees
    - Folder #1 COM.8/25-COM.8/41/Add.1, 1963-70
    - Folder #2 COM.9/85-COM.22/90, 1970
    - Folder #3 COM.22/90-COM.22/109, 1970 (Box Series IV-2)
    - Folder #4 COM.22/110-COM.22/164, 1970-71
  - Board of Governors/
    provisional records of committees
    - Folder #1 COM.8/OR.29-COM.18/OR.5, 1967-70
    - Folder #2 COM.20/OR.5-COM.21/OR.1, 1969-70
    - Folder #3-4 COM.22/OR.1-COM.22/OR.64, 1970
  - Board of Governors/DEC/52 (XI)-64 (XIV), 1968-70 (Box Series IV-3)
    decision summaries
  - Board of Governors/DEC/INDEX/8, 1970
    index to summaries of Board's decisions
  - Board of Governors/DOCS/126/Add. 1-170/Add.1, 1967-71
    documents issued
  - Board of Governors/
    misc. info.
    - Folder #1 INF/165/mod.1-INF/213, 1967-69
    - Folder #2 INF/214-INF/231, 1969-70
  - Board of Governors/OR.394-433, 1968-70
    provisional & official records of mtgs.
  - Calendars and invitations
    - Folder #1, 1960-61
    - Folder #2, 1962
    - Folder #3, 1963-64
    - Folder #4, 1965-66
    - Folder #5, 1967 (Box Series IV: 4)
    - Folder #6, 1968-69
    - Folder #7, 1970
    - Folder #8, 1977
      20th anniv.
  - China, n.d.
  - Committee on U.S. policy toward IAEA
    Brady, E. L.
    Cleveland, [Harlan]
    Eisenbud, Merril
    Farley, Philip J.
    Haskins, Caryl
    Perkinson, Jesse D.
    Yeomans, W. L.
    -See also Ser. IX, U.S. policy toward IAEA
    - Folder #1-2, 1962
      drafts
    - Folder #3, 1961-62
      misc. corresp. & notes
  - Consultants meeting on the question of establishment of an International Centre for Nuclear Medicine under the joint auspices of IAEA..., 1965
  - Delegations, 1962-67
    attendees lists; directories
  - Department of State: Instructions for meeting of the IAEA Board of Governors, 1961
  - Department of State misc., 1964-65
    Thomas, C. W.
  - Department of State. Press releases, 1962
    re: HDS
  - Department of State. Telegrams, 1972
  - Department of State. U.S. position on the future role of the Inter-American Nuclear Energy Commission, 1962
    Stranger, E. L.
  - Diaries, 1959-62 (Box Series IV-5)
    -See also Calendars & invitations
  - Disarmament
    Thompson, Richard S.
    - Folder #1, 1962-65
    - Folder #2, 1966-67
  - Draft summary of discussion concerning IAEA Plasma Physics, 1959
  - European Atomic Energy Community (EURATOM)
    -See Ser. IX, Treaty establishing the European Atomic Energy Community. EURATOM agreement
  - Facilities under U.S. safeguards, 1966; n.d.
  - Financing of IAEA safeguards costs, 1964
    Hefner, Frank K.
    Hope-Jones, Ronald C.
    Meagher, Blanche M.
    Yeomans, William L.
    memo of conversation
  - Forecast of voluntary contributions to the general fund, 7 Nov. 1967
  - Fuel fabrication plant safeguards with U.S., U.K. and Canada. Meeting on, 8-9 Nov. 1967
  - General and safeguards, 1959-65
  - General Conference #9, 1965
    Audrieth, L. F.
  - General Conference #13, 1969
  - General Conference #18. Report of the U.S. delegation to the, 16-20 Sep. 1974
    Porter, Dwight
  - General Conference #21, 1977
  - General Conference/
    agenda items & reports
    - Folder #1 (1) / 1-(XIII) 427, 1957-69
    - Folder #2 (XIII) / 104-(XV) / 455, 1970-71 (Box Series IV-6)
    - Folder #3 (XV) / 459-(XVII) / 500, 1970-73
    - Folder #4 (XVII) / 504-(XVIII) / 526, 1972-80
    - Folder #5 (XIX) / 544-(XX) / 565, 1974-75
    - Folder #6 (XX) / 566-(XX) / 571 / Rev. 1, 1975-77 (Box Series XV: 7)
    - Folder #7-8 (XX) / 571 / Rev. 2-(XXII) / 599, 1977-78
    - Folder #9 (XXII) / 600-(XXIII) / 609, 1979-84
    - Folder #10 (XXIII) / 610-(XXIV) / 628, 1978-80
    - Folder #11 (XXIV) / 630-(XXIV) / 639, 1980-86
  - General Conference (XIII) / COM.1/110-(XXI) / COM.5/6, 1969-77
    committee agendas
  - General Conference/
    records of meetings
    - Folder #1 (XIII) / COM. 1 / OR. 84-(XIII) / COM. 1 / OR. 88, 1970
    - Folder #2 (XV) / COM. 1 / OR. 94-(XXIII) / COM. 5 / OR. 18, 1971-80
  - General Conference (XI) / DOCS / 76-(XXIII) / DOCS / 183 / Mod. 1, 1967-80
    lists of docs. issued
  - General Conference (XIII) / GEN / 35, 1969
    general comm.
  - General Conference (XIII) / GEN / OR. 17, 1970
    records of general comm.
  - General Conference/ (Box Series IV:8)
    - Folder #1 (II) / INF / 16-(XV) / INF / 133 / Rev. 2, 1958-72
    - Folder #2 (XVI) / INF / 137-(XVIII) / INF / 148, 1971-73
    - Folder #3 (XIX) / INF / 154-(XX) / INF / 166, 1974-76
    - Folder #4 (XXI) / INF / 169-(XXI) / INF / 175, 1976-77
    - Folder #5 (XXII) / INF / 177-(XXIV) / INF / 193 / Rev. 3 / Mod. 1, 1977-80
  - General Conference. Journal, 1976-80
  - General Conference/
    - Folder #1 (XI) / OR. 116-(XVI) / OR. 154, 1971-73
    - Folder #2 (XVI) / OR. 155-(XXI) / OR. 195, 1972-77
    - Folder #3 (XXI) / OR. 196-(XXIII) / OR. 218, 1977-80
  - General Conference (XIII) / RESOLUTIONS (1967) - (XXIV) / RES / 378, 1967-80 (Box Series IV-9)
    resolutions & decisions
  - General Conference / RES / INDEX / 1957-71-RES / INDEX / 1977-79, 1957-79
    index to resolutions & decisions
  - General Conference press releases C / X / 8-XXIX / 2, 1966-85
  - Governmental ICY committee on peaceful uses inventory, 21 May 1965
  - High energy accelerators. Minutes of discussions, 1964
  - History of the IAEA, 1963; 1983
    Castle, Emery N.
    Hall, John Allen
    Hamburg, David
    Scheinman, Lawrence
    Smyth, Mary
  - Information Circular/
    - Folder #1 2 / Rev. 2-32 / Mod. 1, 1960-80
    - Folder #2 34/ Add. 4-127 / Mod. 1, 1967-80
    - Folder #3 129-153, 1969-77
    - Folder #4 154-169, 1971-78
    - Folder #5 170-180, 1973-79
    - Folder #6 181-197, 1973-77
    - Folder #7 198-214, 1973-78 (Box Series IV-10)
    - Folder #8 215-229, 1973-80
    - Folder #9 230-246, 1974-77
    - Folder #10 247-263, 1974-78
    - Folder #11 264-282, 1973-80
  - Interim International Nuclear Data Committee (INDC), 29 May-3 Jun. 1967
  - International Centre for Theoretical Physics, 1963-68; n.d.
    [Trieste]
    -See also Ser. I, Salam, Abdus
    -See also Ser. XIII, Smyth,
    Henry DeWolf (20 Jun. 1968)
  - International Centre for Theoretical Physics. Interim report, Jun. 1967
  - International Centre for Theoretical Physics. Monthly Bulletin No. 5, May 1967
  - Italian plan, 1970
    HDS telegram
  - Misc., [1966-70?]; n.d. (Box Series IV-11)
  - Netherlands government to the Council of Ministers of EURATOM on inspection and control in Eurochemic. Memo from the, 26 Oct. 1966
  - Nonproliferation Treaty
    Bennett, C. A.
    Crowsen, Delmar L.
    Edwards, Raymond R.
    George, D. E.
    Grady, Paul
    Kinderman, E. M.
    Strauser, Wilbur
    Tingey, F. H.
    - Folder #1, 1968
    - Folder #2, 1968-69
  - Nonproliferation Treaty (committee)
    Hafele, W.
    european safeguards
    - Folder #1, 1959-68
    - Folder #2-3, 1968
  - Note on assisting programming and utililization of research reactors in lesser-developed areas, 1962
  - Novosibirsk incident. The, 1968
    HDS ms. notes re: meetings on plasma physics
  - Office of international conferences, 1961
  - Offices and officers dealing with IAEA matters
  - Organizational chart, 1962
    -See also oversize
  - Outline of significant facts relating to major activities performed by the IAEA, ca. 1961
  - Pre-Moscow meeting of EANDC members, 26 May 1967
    -See Interim International Nuclear Data Committee (INDC)
  - [Press release]: HDS is sworn in as U.S. representative to the IAEA, 15 Jun. 1961
  - Press releases
    - Folder #1 68/2-13, 1968
    - Folder #2-4 69/52-88, 1969
    - Folder #5-6 70/10-76, 1970
    - Folder #7 71/14-28, 1971
    - Folder #8 75/12-76/23, 1975-76
    - Folder #9 77/12-78/24, 1977-78
    - Folder #10 79/18-82/15, 1979-82
    - Folder #11 84/17-86/6, 1984-86
  - Problems associated with implementing Article III of the NPT, 11 Mar. 1970
  - Provisional agenda for the Board's meetings, Jun. 1965
  - Randers group on conversion and fabrication plants, 1967 (Box Series IV-12)
  - [Reception], 28 Jul. 1970
    guest list for HDS
  - Report from the Secretary of State's panel on the IAEA, 1971
  - Report of the U.S. delegation to the 10th regular session of the General Conference of the IAEA, 21-28 Sep. 1966
  - Report on discussions held in Bangkok concerning the Thai reactor hazard evaluation, 1962
  - Resignation, 1969-90
    background data; MdeCS ms. & typescript notes, drafts
  - [Resignation scrapbook], 1970-71
    Bengelsdorf, Hal
    Goswami, U. L.
    Gough, Betty
    Jacques, Phil
    Kratzer, Myron
    Labowitz, Allan
    Mauritz, Komad
    Najar, Johanna
    Noziglia, Ed
    O'Donnell, Ashton J.
    Sousa, David A.
    Thomas, Carl
    Trevithick, John
    Vanderryn, Jack
    Van Doren, Charles N.
    Yeomans, Bill
    Zook, Donovan Q.
    assembled by MdeCS
  - Safeguards
    drafts & printed notes, memos, reports
    - Folder #1, 1962-64
    - Folder #2, 1965-66; n.d.
  - Schedule of consultations on IAEA Scientific Advisory Committee, [1961?]
    Friedman, A. S.
    reports
    - Folder #1, 1964-65
    - Folder #2, 1969
  - Scientific Advisory Committee. Agenda, May 1961
  - [Scientifie Advisory Committee. Proposed changes in], n.d.
  - Social usage abroad, 1967
    pamphlet
  - [Staff nationalities], 31 Dec. 1960
  - Study Group
    Astin, Allen V.
    Brady, Edward
    Coheen, Meyer
    Comar, Cyril L.
    Tape, Gerald F.
    Trevithick, John P.
    on safeguards and future U.S. policy
    - Folder #1, 1970-71
    - Folder #2, 1971 (Box Series IV-13)
    - Folder #3, 1972; n.d.
  - Tarapur Project, 1962-63; n.d.
    Bhabha, Homi J.
    Chakravarti, M. N.
    Thomas, Charles W.
    Wells, Algie
    nuclear power in India
  - Third U.N. International Conference on the Peaceful Uses of Atomic Energy, 1963-64
    Gardner, Edward R.
    Kane, John H.
    Wells, Algie A.
  - Toll enrichment arrangements, 1966
    includes info. on uranium supplies
  - Transfer of IAEA safeguards to EURATOM. Memo on, 12 Sep. 1966
    HDS draft
  - Trip reports: China, Japan, Philippines, 1965
  - U.S.S.R. visit, 1969
    -See also Ser. I, Morokhov, [?]
    of HDS
  - United Nations General Assembly, 1974-78
  - United Nations Industrial Development Organization. Industrial Development Board, 1968
    re: applications
  - U.S. bilateral agreements on peaceful uses of atomic energy, 1962
  - U.S.-German discussions on NPT held in Washington. Minutes of, 29-31 Oct. 1969
  - [U.S. government support of IAEA], n.d.
  - [U.S. mission budget], 1969
  - U.S. objectives in the IAEA, 7 Feb. 1971
    HDS memo
  - U.S. policy toward the IAEA
    -See Ser. IV, Committee on U.S. policy toward IAEA
    -See Ser. IX, U.S. policy toward the IAEA
  - U.S. voluntary contributions to the IAEA for fiscal year 1965
  - Visit reports to Kurchatov Institute, Obninsk and Dubna
  - [Waldheim luncheon], 23 Jul.
    guest list
  - Western suppliers group meetings, 1964-67
    Mahy, John F., Jr.
    records of mtgs.
- Series V. Smyth Report, 1940-1974
  contains material consulted and generated by Smyth while preparing for the publication of Atomic Energy for Military Purposes, 1945 (the Smyth Report). This series houses some of the most noteworthy documents of the Smyth Papers. Correspondence, notes, drafts, and early printed versions of Smyth's authoritative book on the Manhattan Project provide a detailed record of his preliminary research and writings. Much of this preparatory material as well as the final drafts of Smyth's report on the technical aspects of the atomic bomb remained classified until its official release by the U.S. government in August of 1945. For this reason, nearly all of the documents of Series V bear original "Secret" and "Top Secret" stamps, which have since been marked declassified by the U.S. AEC.
  Many of the various formats of Smyth Report material (i.e., correspondence, notes, manuscripts) are related in several ways. Researchers should note that Series V is retained in its original order, as arranged by Smyth during his lifetime. Often these documents contain specific references to each other, which appears to be Smyth's primary reason for maintaining a detailed inventory and separate storage system for his Smyth Report material. Also, these documents periodically underwent classification review by the AEC as a group and were downgraded to "Unclassified" in parts. Since these materials remained together over the years for a variety of reasons, they have been retained in their original order rather than separated by format and filed into other series.
  The container list for this series reflects the order of brown envelopes and a "red box" arranged by Smyth (see the first folder of Series V, Box #1 for HDS manuscript "Contents of brown envelopes in third drawer of five drawer file"). The original envelopes and "red box" have been discarded, with their contents transferred to acid-free folders and placed in the standard size archival boxes used throughout the Smyth collection. Researchers will find that any notation from these original envelopes has been photocopied and placed at the front of Folder #1 for each envelope. As Smyth's table of contents and the subsequent container list will show, the documents of Series V generally follow a chronological arrangement, with the bulk of the material dating from 1944-1945.
  The Series V portion of the container list follows the same basic format as the rest of the Smyth Papers series, with the exception of occasional areas of text. This text appears in bold at the beginning of each numbered "envelope" and duplicates the manuscript notes written by Smyth in his table of contents. These notes are transcribed exactly as written by Smyth, with occasional additions in brackets for further explanation. Researchers should see the photocopy of the original envelope front, located in the first folder for each envelope, for further manuscript notes by Smyth. Each area of text describing the general contents of an envelope is followed by a container list which duplicates the arrangement of the folders in Box #1-4. Detailed listings of the pagination (i.e., I-1 to 7 refers to Chapter I, pages 1 to 7) for each folder also appears on the container list.